Jeannette Thurber Connor Collection of Floridiana
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Jeannette Thurber Connor Collection of Floridiana 1570-1927
MSS16642
Connor, Jeannette Thurber, d. 1927
4,500 items
23 containers plus 1 oversize
11 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Historian. Correspondence, research material, reports, writings, speeches, photographs, and transcripts of documents in French, Spanish, and English repositories relating to the early history of Florida.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Connor, Jeannette Thurber, 1872-1927.
Organizations
Archivo General de Indias.
Places
Florida--History--To 1821.; Florida--History.; Spain--Colonies--America.
Occupations
Historians.
Provenance
The Floridiana collection of Jeannette Thurber Connor, historian, was given to the Library of Congress by Connor in 1923. Additions were given by her husband Washington Everett Connor, 1929-1930.
Additional Guides
Card indexes for certain files are available in the Manuscript Reading Room.
Access and Restrictions
The collection of Jeannette Thurber Connor is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Jeannette Thurber Connor, born 1872, became interested in researching the early history of Florida after her marriage to Washington Everett Connor in 1913. Following her investigation into the background of a Spanish mission on her husband's Florida estate, Connor began her research into the early Spanish settlements and missions of Florida. She accumulated transcripts and photocopies of original letters, reports, and other documents of Spanish officials of Florida from 1570 to the beginning of the eigthteenth century that had been preserved in Spanish repositories, especially the Archivo General de Indias, Seville, Spain. Together with John B. Stetson (1884-1952), Connor founded the Florida State Historical Society in 1921 and began a publication project of Florida historical studies supported by the society. Among the volumes Connor translated and edited for the series were Pedro Menéndez de Avilés: Memorial by Gonzalo Solis de Merás (De Land, Fla.: Florida State Historial Society, 1923); Colonial Records of Spanish Florida, 2 vols. (De Land, Fla.: Florida State Historial Society, 1925 and 1930); and The Whole and True Discouerye of Terra Florida (De Land, Fla.: Florida State Historial Society, 1927). Connor died on June 9, 1927 in New York, N.Y. Upon Connor's death and following financial losses suffered by Stetson in 1929, the Florida State Historical Society was discontinued and its publishing program terminated.
Scope and Content Note
The collection of Floridiana of Jeannette Thurber Connor (1872-1927) spans the years 1570-1927. The collection is in English, Spanish, and French and is organized into the following series: Correspondence, Writings, Speeches, Transcripts, and Oversize.
The Connor collection contains correspondence, research material, reports, writings, speeches, notes, photographs, printed matter, and transcripts and photocopies of documents in repositories relating to the early history of Florida and represents a selective assemblage of material concerning Spanish Florida gathered by Connor on subjects of interest to her. The Correspondence series primarily concerns Connor's research and transcription efforts at the Archivo General de Indias, Seville, Spain, while Writings contains her research notes, drafts, and source material for miscellaneous writings and research projects, including files relating to Jean Ribaut, author of Connor's commemorative edition of The Whole and True Discouerye of Terra Florida. The Speeches series consists of a report addressed to the annual meeting of the Florida State Historical Society by Connor and a brief talk given by her to a history class at John B. Stetson University, De Land, Fla. The Transcripts series contains the transcript and photocopied reproductions of primary documents collected by Connor for her research at the Archivo General de Indias, Seville, Spain, as well as other repositories.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged in five series:
Correspondence, 1914-1927
Writings, 1570-1927
Speeches, 1926
Transcripts, undated
Oversize, circa 1590-1796
Container List
- Correspondence, 1914-1927 (Box 1-2)
  Correspondence and miscellaneous material primarily relating to the Archivo General de Indias, Seville, Spain
  Arranged by type of correspondence and therein chronologically.
  - General, 1914-1927, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Archivo General de Indias, Seville, Spain (Box 1)
    - 1919-1920, June, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1920, July 1920-1923, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
- Writings, 1570-1927 (Box 2-10)
  Drafts, research material, photocopies, photographs, reports, notes, printed matter, proofs, and miscellaneous items relating to Connor's articles, books, and other writings concerning her research into Florida's early history.
  Arranged by title and type of material.
  - "The Case of Mr. John Gordon.. ." (Box 2)
  - "Chronicles of the Florida East Coast" (Box 2)
    - Dedication and preface, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Chapters (Box 2)
      - Chapters 1-8, (8 folders) (Box 2)
      - Chapters 9-19, (12 folders) (Box 3)
    - Research notes and drafts, (2 folders); (7 folders); (1 folder) (Box 3, Box 4, Box 5)
  - Colonial Records of Spanish Florida, vol. 1 (1925), 1570-1577 (Box 5)
    - Draft, (5 folders) (Box 5)
    - Proofs, (1 folder) (Box 5, Box 6)
  - "The Indian River. The St. Johns. The Timucua Indians" (Box 6)
  - "The Old Franciscan Mission of Florida and Georgia and the Indians" (Box 6)
    - Draft (Box 6)
      - Introduction, chapters 1-9, (9 folders) (Box 6)
      - Chapters 10-17, (8 folders) (Box 7)
    - Research notes (Box 8)
  - "Jean Ribaut" (Box 8)
  - Ribaut, Jean, The Whole and True Discouerye of Terra Florida, 1927 (Box 8)
  - "Manuscripts and Letters of Ponce de Leon and Pedro Menéndez de Avilés", (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - "The Memoir of Francisco López de Mendoza Grajales" (Box 8)
  - "The Truth about the Florida Missions for the Franciscan Friars and Their Mission for the Jeroro Indians Near New Smyrna" (Box 8)
  - Research notes (Box 8)
    - New Smyrna, Fla., (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - Notes on various early French priests in America (Box 8)
    - Sheldon family (Box 9)
    - General, (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Research source materials (Box 9)
    - Photocopies (Box 9)
      - Affidavit of notary on ceremony of breaking ground for the erection of the fort (Box 9)
      - Arte y Pronunciación en Lengua Timuquana, y Castellana (Box 9)
      - Buckingham Smith Papers (Box 9)
      - Catechismo y Breve Exposición de la Doctrina Christiana (Box 9)
      - Cathecismo en Lengua Castellana (Box 9)
      - Confessionario en Lengua Castellana (Box 9)
      - Discovrs de l'Histoire de la Floride (Box 9)
      - Letters (Box 9)
        - Council to King, 1579 (Box 9)
        - De Soto, Don Hernando, to the Alcades (Box 9)
        - Montiano, Juan Manuel, to Juan Francisco de Guemes y Honasitas (Box 9)
      - Maps, surveys, illustrations, and narratives, circa 1590, 1733-1796, undated See also Oversize (Box 10)
      - Menéndez, Pedro, Brinton's translation of two letters (Box 10)
      - A Notable Historie Containing Foure Voyages Made by Certayne French Captaynes unto Florida (Box 10)
      - Proclamation: Visitation of the Bishop, 1675 (Box 10)
      - Scisco, L. D. (Box 10)
        - "Ponce De Leon's Patents for Colonization" (Box 10)
        - "The Track of Ponce De Leon in 1513" (Box 10)
      - Unidentified (Box 10)
    - Photographs (Box 10)
    - Printed matter, (2 folders) (Box 10)
- Speeches, 1926 (Box 10)
  Typescripts of two addresses by Connor.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Report at the annual meeting of the Florida State Historical Society, 1926, Feb. (Box 10)
  - "Turtle Mound and the Indian River in 1605," talk to Dean Carson's history class, John B. Stetson University, De Land, Fla., 1926, Mar. (Box 10)
- Transcripts, undated (Box 11-23)
  Transcript and photocopied reproductions of original documents collected by Connor for her research at the Archivo General de Indias, Seville, Spain, as well as other repositories.
  Arranged by repository. Shelf, drawer, and file number locations are provided for each folder of reproduced material from the Archivo General de Indias, Seville, Spain.
  - Archivo General de Indias, Seville, Spain (Box 11)
    - Audiencia de Santo Domingo (Box 11)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file no., 53-1-6 (Box 11)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file nos., 53-2-4, 10, 11, 12, (4 folders) (Box 11)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file nos., 54-1-15, 34, (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file nos., 54-2-2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 17, (7 folders) (Box 11)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file no., 54-3-19 (Box 11)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file no., 54-5-9, (4 folders) (Box 12)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file nos., 54-5-10, 11, 13, 14, (6 folders) (Box 13)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file nos., 54-5-14, 15, 16, 17, (7 folders) (Box 14)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file nos., 54-5-17, 18, 19, 20, (6 folders) (Box 15)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file nos., 54-5-20; 58-1-20, 25, 26, 27, (6 folders) (Box 16)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file nos., 58-1-27, 29, 31, 32, (5 folders) (Box 17)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file nos., 58-1-33, 34, 35, 36, (4 folders) (Box 18)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file nos., 58-2-2, 5, 6, (3 folders) (Box 18)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file nos., 58-2-8, 12, 14, 15, (5 folders) (Box 19)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file nos., 58-2-16, 17, (2 folders) (Box 20)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file no., 78-2-2 (Box 20)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file no., 79-4-2 (Box 20)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file no., 86-6-5 (Box 20)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file nos., 86-7-1, 11, 21, (3 folders) (Box 20)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file no., 87-1-3 (Box 20)
      - Shelf, drawer, and file no., 87-3-27 (Box 20)
    - Audiencia de Mexico, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - Indiferente General, (2 folders); (22 folders) (Box 20, Box 21)
    - Papeles de Cuba (Box 21)
    - Patronato, (2 folders); (8 folders) (Box 21, Box 22)
    - Escribania de Cámara, (2 folders) (Box 22, Box 23)
    - Contratación, (3 folders) (Box 23)
    - Contaduría (Box 23)
  - Biblioteca Nacional, Madrid, Spain (Box 23)
  - Bibliotèque Nationale, Paris, France (Box 23)
  - Brooks transcripts (Box 23)
  - British Museum, London, England, (3 folders) (Box 23)
  - Public Record Office, London, England, Colonial Office 5 (Box 23)
- Oversize, circa 1590-1796 (Box OV 1)
  Maps, surveys, illustrations, and narratives.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Writings (Box OV 1)
    - Research source materials (Box OV 1)
      - Photocopies (Box OV 1)
        - Maps, surveys, illustrations, and narratives, circa 1590, 1733-1796, undated (Container 10) (Box OV 1)